Name: Eduardo Rinaldi

Born: 20/11/1998 in Naples, Italy **E-mail:** eduardo.rinaldi1998@gmail.com

Website: edu-rinaldi.github.io

SUMMARY

Since January 2023, I am a Junior Gameplay Programmer at Ubisoft Berlin. In 2022, while I was achieving my Master's degree in Computer Science at Sapienza University of Rome, I also worked on a research thesis about practical algorithms for diffing and merging node-graph based programs. Before that, in 2020 I graduated with my Bachelor's degree, presenting algorithms for improving adaptability for iris-based recognition systems. Graphics and GPU programming are currently a side hustle that I work on whenever I have free time.

SKILLS

- Programming languages: C, C++, Python, Java, JavaScript, SQL, ASM Mips
- Graphics programming: Physically based ray-tracing, Multiple importance sampling, Volumetric rendering, OpenGL API, GLSL Shading programming, Ray-marching
- Game programming: basic knowledge of Unreal Engine 4 and Unity, Object-oriented programming and Entity-Component system
- Al techniques: Supervised learning, Clustering, Reinforcement learning, Convolutional neural networks, Big data computing techniques
- Maths: strong linear algebra and probability knowledge
- Soft skills: team working, ability to meet deadlines in time, problem-solving and interpersonal skills

MASTERCLASS

 O'LNOLAGO	
Game Design and Gamification lab	Oct. 2021
Prof. Francesco Lutrario – Sapienza University of Rome	
Fundamentals of Computer Graphics	Oct. 2021
Prof. Fabio Pellacini – Sapienza University of Rome	
Computer Graphics	Mar. 2020
Prof. Fabio Pellacini – Sapienza University of Rome	
 ·	

EXPERIENCE

Junior Gameplay Programmer - Ubisoft Berlin

Unannounced project.

Research thesis: NodeDiff – Sapienza University of Rome Mar. 2022 - Oct. 2022

Jan. 2023 - Present

Design and implementation of Diffing and Merging algorithms for visual scripting graphs to enable versioning. Framework (*NodeDiff*) implementation in C++, providing test examples on *Blender's* shading and geometry node graphs.

Research internship: Iris recognition system - Sapienza University of Aug. 2020 - Dec. 2020 Rome

Porting of the *ISis v2* Iris Recognition System into C++ with improved performance and adaptivity through computer vision techniques.

EDUCATION

Sapienza University of Rome Master's degree in Computer Science, 110/110 with honours – Rome, Italy	Oct. 2022
Sapienza University of Rome	Dec. 2020
Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, 110/110 with honours - Rome, Italy	
ITIS I Trafelli	July 2017.

Secondary school diploma in IT, 100/100 - Nettuno, Italy